Guide to the Betty Fong Chinese-American family photographs, 1931-1976 MS 851
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Betty Fong Chinese-American family photographs
1931-1976
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Fong, Betty
MS 851
2 Linear Feet 1 box
The collection contains family photos of the Gor, Chow, and Fong families, with 2 pages of biographical information.
Biographical / Historical
Families immigrated to Texas from China and have lived in Waco, San Antonio, Houston, as well as Los Angeles and Boston. Shok Ling Gor (the father of Fay Yook Gor and three other sons) was a San Francisco paper son in the 1930s who was joined by Fay Yook Gor in 1936. Fay Yook Gor returned to China and married Foy Kin Chow in 1947. Fay Yook Gor then moved to Houston in 1949, opening the Fay Food Market. By 1968 Fay Kin Chow became a naturalized citizen and took the name Fay Kin Gor. The other sons of Shok Ling Gor spread across America while Fay Yook Gor continued to build a life for his family across Houston.
Content Description
Family photos of the Gor, Chow, and Fong families, with 2 pages of biographical information.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Betty Fong via the Chao Center for Asian Studies, 2019.
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Asians -- America -- History; Social life and customs
Document Types
photographs
Places
Asian Americans
Subjects (Persons)
Fong, Betty
- Family photographs
  - The Fay Yook Gor Family, 1958 (Box 114, Item 1)
  - The Fay Yook Gor Family, 1956 (Box 114, Item 2)
  - The Fay Yook Gor Family, 1956 (Box 114, Item 3)
  - Foy Kin Chow (Box 114, Item 4)
  - Shok Ling Gor (O.Y. Jung, OW Yang Jung, Eddie Gor) (Box 114, Item 5)
  - The Fay Yook Gor Family, 1976 (Box 114, Item 6)
  - Fay Yook Gor, 1923-2007 (Box 114, Item 7)
  - Fay Yook Gor (Box 114, Item 8)
  - Foy Kin Chow (Foy Kin Ow-Yang) (Box 114, Item 9)
  - Fay Yook Gor (Seated Left of Photo) (Box 114, Item 10)
  - Fay Y. Gor (Pictured Standing on Right) (Box 114, Item 11)
  - The Ling Shok Gor and Bill O.Y. Ong Families (Box 114, Item 12)
  - Yok Jee Chow (Box 114, Item 13)
  - Art Yook Gor (4 Son of Shok Ling Gor), 1962 (Box 114, Item 14)
  - The Shok Ling Gor Family Photo, 1952 (Box 114, Item 15)
  - Len Yook Gor and Helen Wong (Box 114, Item 16)
  - Len Yook Gor and Helen Wong (Wedding Group Photo) (Box 114, Item 17)
  - First Baptist Church Waco, Tx., Spring 1952 (Box 114, Item 18)
  - Ling Shok Gor Family Photo, 1965 (Box 114, Item 19)
  - Mrs. Len Gor (Helen Wong), Mrs. Yet Oy Lee, Mrs. Fay Y. Gor, 1971 (Box 114, Item 20)
  - Art Yook Gor, 1962 (Box 114, Item 21)
  - Jue Yuen Chow, 1931 (Box 114, Item 22)
  - Jue Yuen Chow (Box 114, Item 23)